<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android on Iqbal Ahmed</title><link>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in Android on Iqbal Ahmed</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 12:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dastaniqbal.github.io/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convert icomoon.io Font to Android icons.xml</title><link>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-16-convert-icomoon-io-font-to-android-icons-xml/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 12:29:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-16-convert-icomoon-io-font-to-android-icons-xml/</guid><description>We had the requirement to use icomoon.io font file. but we had the concerned when we update font file, its changed icon hexcode. and we wanted to use those hexcode everywhere in our project.
We have written mapping strings xml file in which we were using demo.html file and using icon name as our key and hexcode as our value, but when we update icon name, icon name remain same but hexcode change.</description></item><item><title>How to use Epoxy with Databinding (PART 3)</title><link>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-28-how-to-use-epoxy-with-databinding-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 08:09:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-28-how-to-use-epoxy-with-databinding-part-3/</guid><description>Like in previous Part we have seen how simple to list item using Epoxy ViewHolder.
In this post, we gonna use Databinding to list items on RecyclerView/EpoxyRecyclerView
Listing with Epoxy databinding is bit different, like in android we do databinding by defining &amp;lt;data&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/data&amp;gt; block or using BindingAdapter. In Epoxy we use these features directly and we don&amp;rsquo;t write any extra class to handle all these functions.
3. Show List using Databinding</description></item><item><title>How to use Epoxy with ViewHolder (Part 2)</title><link>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-22-airbnb-epoxy-with-viewholder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 10:06:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-08-22-airbnb-epoxy-with-viewholder/</guid><description>Like in previous part we have seen how simple to list item using data class.
In this post, we gonna use View Holder to list items on RecyclerView/EpoxyRecyclerView
Listing with ViewHolder is similar like Recycler.ViewHolder but in Epoxy we extend to EpoxyModelWithHolder
2. Show List using ViewHolder
Here we need a helper class KotlinEpoxyHolder that we can get from epoxy sample or from our source code.
package com.dastnaiqbal.epoxysample.helper import android.view.View import com.</description></item><item><title>How to use Epoxy in Android (Part 1)</title><link>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-06-26-how-to-use-epoxy-in-android-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 12:49:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dastaniqbal.github.io/blog/2020-06-26-how-to-use-epoxy-in-android-part-1/</guid><description>Like automation is evolving in a different sector. how it&amp;rsquo;s evolving in Android. As we know about autogenerated code where we use a bunch of annotations and its auto write code for you with the help of kapt and annotationProcessor We know many plugins which write boilerplate code for you For eg Dagger.
Same we are moving to declarative programming like JetPack Compose and Litho. The same Airbnb changes the way to show the list by using Epoxy.</description></item></channel></rss>